Hello friends, my name is Sachin and
I welcome you to our channel
and today we are going to discuss about no claim
bonus, what is no claim bonus
and how does it work in the policy,
so friends see, whenever
you take insurance from any company, there is
a feature in it which we call no claim
bonus, you can understand the meaning of this bonus as no,
but in the year in which you did
not make a claim, the companies will
give you a bonus and gradually they will keep
adding it to your basic insurance and
this gradually increases your Someshwar, so
let us know a little about which
companies in the market and how do they
add bonus to Someshwar, so
first of all there is an option of ten
percent in which every claim free year means that
even this year you have not made a claim,
ten percent will be added to it and this
maximum goes up to 50%, the second option is
that only ten percent will give you no claim bonus
and it will go up to hundred percent or
not, if you have a policy of Rs 5 lakh then
550000 in the next years, then six lakhs the next year,
doing this in this way, at the time of hundred percent, there is
an option in
which they give 20% and the same also goes up
to hundred percent maximum, many
companies these days are providing
50% no
claim bonus in the very new innovative labs that are coming up and yours is
taken up to hundred percent,
if we talk about its benefits, then
here we understand from a PAN
table that
if we look at mine in this, the base time limit is
₹1000000 and if I have
not taken any claim in the first year, then I will
get a benefit of 50% in it, so
my policy will be worth Rs 1500000.
Similarly, if I have
not taken any claim from the company in the second year also,
then it will become Rs 5 lakh, so the total
total which if I do after my second year
i.e. third year  If I talk about it, then
leaving aside my total time, whether I will have a boy or not,
which was my best policy of 10 lakhs,
if we add 50% to it, then after 2 years,
that policy will become mine of 20 lakhs.
Why do companies give this, actually, what is it?
Whenever you take any plan, then you pay
its premium, if you do
not make a claim, then that premium does
not come back in health insurance, so that is why the
company gives you some additional benefits.
Now let us
discuss here that where
we have added a no claim bonus of only 10 percent,
so firstly, we have
always taken ₹1000000 as base here, in the first year, we will add one lakh
rupees to it, in the second year, another
one lakh will be added to it, so
leaving aside the total time, after two years it will become 12 lakh rupees
and here it was made for 2000000 rupees,
so we should try, we should
take an airplane in such a way that we
get more no claim bonus, that is, the
cover of our body is more than this  It will increase a lot,
we are talking about what will be our benefit
if a claim comes, then how will this no
claim bonus work, so let us understand
that if a claim comes, then here
I have explained to you two ways, first let us
understand that in this one, first of all, I have a policy of
Rs. 1000000, here in the first year
I got a no claim bonus of 50%, that is
my total policy
in the second year it became ₹1500000, now in the second year
my policy is considered to be of 15 lakh
rupees, that I went to the hospital for treatment
and my bill came up to 15 lakh rupees, so
if your bill is of 15 lakh rupees, then
that will become your total, but
you will not get any no claim bonus in the third year
because no claim bonus is
given when you have not made any claim in the previous year,
now let us come to this,
look here the base sum
is ₹10, from the first year we have given 50 percent no
claim bonus  I have done this i.e. Rs 5 lakh,
so the policy that I got for the second year,
after the second year, that my policy went up to
Rs 1500000, now here I am saying
that if a claim of Rs 10 comes, then
what will happen, so see, the claim that has come for
Rs 10 lakh will be enough for you,
but the bonus of Rs 5 lakh that was left will
not be carried forward, it will
not be added in the next year because
this is the rule of the companies that if we increase your 50%, then
we will also reduce it by 50%, so it is
very important to understand this thing friends that
in the same rates in which your no claim bonus increases i.e. 10%, 20% or 50
%,
it also decreases in the same rates, so
here, in this,
nothing will be added to your no claim bonus for the next year
nor will it be carried forward and the
remaining amount here was Rs 5000 because
our total here was Rs 15 lakh and we have taken the
base only i.e. total time taken.  If
we had taken a black policy then next year if that sum is
zero then we will
not get any bonus here
except the base term which is ₹1000000
and from the third year onwards our policy will run for 10 lakhs
only. So I hope you have understood this information.
If you like my videos
then please like and
subscribe to it and
also tell your friends that in such health insurance, whatever is
going on in our body, how
important are these small points
and how do they work.
Thank you very much for watching this video.